Masashi Kondo

Software Engineer

000-0000-0000 | Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada linkedin.com/in/masashi-kondo | github.com/MssKnd

SUMMARY

As a Software Engineer with over 10 years of experience specializing in Web Frontend, I solve technical challenges and ensure development needs align with business goals. With a decade of experience, I excel in TypeScript and React. Skilled in backend development, Web Standard API, and CI/CD with GitHub Actions. I facilitate team communication and productivity, leading teams to higher efficiency. Speaker at GDG DevFest 2020 Tokyo.

EXPERIENCE

CEO / Full Stack Software Engineer (Self-employed)

June 2022 – Present

Rokka LLC

Kumamoto, Japan

- Developed SaaS products for startups, focusing on high-cohesion, loosely-coupled systems.
- Designed and implemented a Design System to ensure consistency and e ffi ciency in UI/UX.
- Addressed performance issues related to displaying and manipulating large datasets in web front-end applications, improving memory efficiency and reducing rendering time from 1 minute to 5 seconds.
- As a Scrum Master, enhanced Scrum events' efficiency, doubling meeting productivity and improving feedback cycles, which resulted in a 20% increase in overall team productivity.

Software Engineer / Web Frontend Engineer Safie Inc.

December 2018 – March 2022

Tokyo, Japan

- Developed a cloud-based video viewer with Angular for IoT camera services.
- Integrated machine learning with network camera images and developed a canvas drawing application for image annotation.
- Successfully led the adoption of Scrum during the team's growth from 2 to 6 members, overseeing velocity tracking and visualization to stabilize the development process.

Network Engineer

July 2013 – December 2018

SoftBank Corp.

Tokyo, Japan

- Maintained dedicated line systems and developed web applications.
- Designed and implemented international VPN and network systems.

EDUCATION

Master of Kansei Science

April 2011 – March 2013

 $Kyushu\ University$

Bachelor of Computer Science

April 2009 – March 2011

Kumamoto National College of Technology

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

TypeScript, Deno, JavaScript, Kotlin, HTML/CSS

Frameworks & Libraries:

React, Hono, Angular, Vue.js, SWR, jest, Storybook, Playwright, Spring boot

Tools & Platforms:

Git, GitHub Actions, Supabase, PostgreSQL, Bun, Docker, AWS

Other:

Web Standard API, DDD, Agile methodologies, Network technology

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Applied Information Technology Engineer
- Network Specialist
- ITIL FOUNDATION V3

References available upon request.